

Jeremiah Bhasme

CONTACT

jeremiah.bhasme@gmail.com +91 900 868 4554

310, 3rd Main, 6th Cross Road, OMBR Layout, 560043 Bangalore, India

DIGITAL SKILLS

Database

MySQL

Frameworks:

Bootstrap Codelgniter Ruby on Rails

Programming and Scripting Languages:

CSS HTML/HTML5 JavaScript PHP

Ruby

SCSS

Project Management:

Confluence

Jira

Trello

Trac

Technology Stack:

LAMP

Version Control:

BitBucked/GitHub

Git

PROFILE

Developer with over 10 years of international experience in providing 3-teir web solutions. Experienced in PHP, Ruby, Bootstrap, Codelgniter and Ruby on Rails. Dependable, adept and experienced in working in teams with members from diverse backgrounds.

WORK EXPERIENCE

17/01/2013 - 31/05/2022 - Bangalore, India

IT Administrator

MacBrout Engineering Pvt. Ltd.

- Built mock designs and wireframes for landing pages of the three companyassociated websites using Pencil and translated designs into high-quality code using HTML, CSS/SASS and JavaScript
- Reengineered websites using appropriate technologies (Codelgniter, MySQL, WordPress) to run the site on a shared host and helped reduce estimated hosting costs by around 60%
- Redesigned the front-end using Bootstrap CSS framework to make sites more accessible and user-friendly

01/06/2012 - 01/11/2012 - Bangalore, India

Senior Research Analyst (Quality)

SEEK Research Solutions

 Checked if the company profiles created by data entry operators met the standards set.

01/08/2010 - 31/05/2012 - Bangalore, India

IT Support Specialist

THE K. J. V. Bible Society

- Setup and maintained Joomla! based website
- Setup network infrastructure and backup system to share resources between five office computers

01/09/2005 - 01/04/2010 - Crown Point, United States

Junior Developer

Hyles-Anderson College

- Accelerated Yearbook publication by implementing Ruby script to automate redundant tasks. Used the WIN32 API libraries to modify InDesign CS documents
- Developed a Work Reporting and Monitoring system to maintain and generate periodic reports of about 300 students in the work scholarship program. Technologies used include Ruby on Rails framework, Tortise SVN, and MySQL database
- Conceptualized and created Dormitory Room Attendance system with Ruby on Rails, Git and MySQL database to monitor attendance of over 200 dormitory residents

Tortise SVN

Developed a WordPress plugin to populate Google map with alumni locations for a selected region

09/01/2003 - 01/08/2005 - Bangalore, India

Executive assistant

THE K. J. V. Bible Society

- Designed website mock-up and hard-coded website with HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Introduced and implemented MS Access database for record management and office automation

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelors in Religious Education

HYLES-ANDERSON COLLEGE, Crown Point, IN, USA https://hylesanderson.edu/

Junior Software Test Professional – Level 1

THE INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE FOR SOFTWARE TESTING, Bengaluru, KA, INDIA https://testinginstitute.com/

Bachelor of Engineering – Instrumentation & Process control

Karnataka University Dharwad, Hubli, KA, INDIA https://www.kud.ac.in/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Kannada OTHER LANGUAGE(S): English, Hindi

I hereby declare that the information stated above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Bangalore, 22/06/2022